Clement Gendler

LinkedIn: /clement-gendler/ • clementgendler98@gmail.com • clementgendler.github.io • 914-584-3238

About

I enjoy taking on business challenges with an insightful data-driven approach. With experience in data science, data analytics, marketing, and healthcare, I'm an innovator that creatively solves complex problems to improve products and services for clients. Other passions I have besides coding and working with big data are creative writing, actively exploring New York City, and listening to jazz and classic rock music.

Skills

Technical: Python, SQL, R, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Keras, TensorFlow, Natural Language Processing, Git/GitHub, Spark, Data Visualization (Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn, Tableau), HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Java, Statistics **Additional:** Spanish speaker (professional working proficiency), Photoshop, Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint)

Professional Experience

Platform Production Analyst, Crossix Analytics

Jan 2021 - Present New York, NY

Veeva Systems

- Produces and manages DIFA HCP Site, a platform for informing, measuring, and optimizing healthcare marketing
- Uses SQL, Python, Excel, Spark, a logic-based proprietary language, and data visualization tools to produce monthly DIFA deliverables that track site visitation and web analytics
- Analyzes root causes and data anomalies while monitoring and troubleshooting analysis execution
- Automates, plans, and improves internal processes through collaboration with the Engineering team
- Handles client inquiries related to data and DIFA methodology by providing insight to the Client Services team

Data Science Fellow Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

General Assembly

New York, NY

- Completed 480-hour immersive course in python programming and data science
- Solved real-world problems by applying data collection, cleaning, visualization, analysis, modeling, as well as machine learning and deep learning techniques to large data sets
- Predicted a Chess game's outcome with 88% accuracy using only moves played with LSTM and GRU neural networks
- Analyzed and classified 5,000 Reddit posts using Natural Language Processing
- Collaborated with two Data Science Fellows to predict future COVID-19 hotspots

Marketing Analyst Intern

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

Pink Sky, LLC

Scarsdale, NY

- Analyzed qualitative research data for a mattress and personal care company via Excel
- Developed summary analysis for mattress research report, providing companies with insight into consumer choice and gaining an advantage over competing companies
- Designed a research presentation via PowerPoint, placing emphasis on visualizing summary analysis with a diverse variety of charts to illustrate findings

Education

New York University

- B.A. in Economics, Class of 2020, New York, NY
- Buenos Aires Study Abroad August 2017 December 2017

General Assembly

• Python Programming, Certificate of Completion, August 2019